Hello, everyone.
hello，大家好
I am Chao Zhang from the Kylin community.
我是来自麒麟社区的张超
Today, I will share a simple technology sharing on the UKUI3 tablet mode
今天由我就 UKUI3 平板模式进行一个简单的技术分享
First of all, I will introduce the latest development of UKUI
首先介绍一下 UKUI 的当前的一个最新的进展
what results have been achieved and actual application cases
取得了哪些成果和实际的应用 案例
and then I will specifically share some of the main features of the new tablet mode
然后我会具体分享一些新增平板模式的几个主要特性
Finally, let’s talk about the future of UKUI. What are the important points that need to be developed and improved.
最后呢，再来谈一下 UKUI 的未来还有哪些重点需要开发和完善的功能点
First, a simple introduction
首先简单介绍一下 UKUI
UKUI is a lightweight Linux open source desktop environment developed by the Kylin team
UKUI是麒麟团队主导开发的一个轻量级 Linux开源桌面环境
It is currently installed by default in the Ubuntu kylin open source operating system,  the commercial releases of Kylin and the NeoKylin operating system.
当前默认搭载在优麒麟开源操作系统和银河麒麟、中标麒麟操作系统的商业发行版中
UKUI has also been ported to many Linux distributions
UKUI 其实也已经适配了很多国内外主流的 Linux 发行版
such as Debian, Ubuntu, Fedora, and openEuler
比 如 Debian、Ubuntu、Fedora 、OpenEuler
all of which have entered their official repositories
这些都已进入了他们的官方仓库
It will be promoted to more Linux distributions in the future
未来将会推广到更多的 Linux 发行版中
hoping to allow more users and developers to use UKUI quickly and conveniently
希望让更多的用户和开发者能够快速方便地使用UKUI
In addition to the traditional PC mode of UKUI
UKUI除了传统端模式之外呢
this time we also provide a new tablet mode to meet the needs of the tablet application ecology and various usage scenarios.
这次我们也新提供了一个平板模式来满足平 板应用生态和各种使用场景的需求
In this sharing, I want to introduce how UKUI adds a support for the tablet ecosystem on the basis of the traditional Linux desktop
本次的一个分享主要就是想介绍一下 UKUI 是如何在传统的 Linux 桌面基础上
and current support for the tablet devices and future planning
添加对平板生态的一个支持以及未来的规划
and in the process of making the tablet model, we also have some experience and results of some projects and actual products
还有在做平板模式的过程中我们也有一些项目和实际产品的一个经验和成果
to share with you
给大家分享一下
The history of UKUI follows the release of the Ubuntu Kylin
UKUI 历史是随着优麒麟的社区版的发布一 起
UKUI1.0 first release in 2013
UKUI1.0 是 2013 年
it is a simple modification based on Unity7 and Ubuntu7
当时还是基于 Unity 7、Ubuntu 7 进行的一个简单修改
and the modification is about themes and icons
主要还是对主题和图标进行的修改
In 2017, UKUI 2.0 was released
到了 2017 年发布了 UKUI 2.0
At that time, Ubuntu Kylin released a self-developed desktop environment
当时是优麒麟发布一个自己研发的
It like the experience of Windows users.
一个类似 Windows 用户体验的一个自研的 桌面环境
In Ubuntu Kylin 20.04
到了去年也是 20.04 的 时 候
we officially released UKUI 3.0
我们正式发布了 UKUI3.0
The entire UKUI 3.0 was designed by the Ubuntu Kylin team
UKUI 3.0 整 个是由优麒麟团队自行设计的
which formed a set of its own design concept and this interactive concept and completed it
形成了一套自己的设计理念和这个交互的一个理念并研发完成
Here I will give you a brief introduction to the basic technical architecture of UKUI 3.0
这里我给大家简单介绍一下 UKUI3.0 的一个基本技术架构
As shown in the picture, our basic display service is to support X and Wayland at the same time
如图所示，我们基本的显示服务是同时支持 X 和 Wayland
and our basic graphic development library is based on Qt and KF5
基础的图形开发库我们是基于 Qt 和 KF5
At the same time, on the basis of Qt and KF5
同时在 Qt、KF5 基础上
we continue to encapsulate and develop our own advanced interface
我们还在不断的去封装和编写自己的一个高级接口
On this, we have completely rewritten a variety of core desktop components
在此之上，我们完全重写了一个各种核心的桌面组件
including start menu, task panel, sidebar, multitasking view, file manager, etc.
包括开始菜单、任务栏、侧边栏、登录、多任务视图，文件管理器等等
They are more than a dozen core desktop components
十几个桌面核心的组件
On top of this, we also have a lot of desktop environment kits and basic applications
在此之上呢我们还有很多桌面环境的套件基本应用
will be self-developed
也基本会大量自研
it includes the upper desktop environment kit and the core desktop environment components
所以包括上层的桌面环境套件以及核心的桌面环境组件
and some basic desktop environment graphics development libraries
以及一些基本的桌面环境的图形开发库
They formed a basic structure of our existing UKUI
这些包含在一起形成了我们现有的一个UKUI的一个基本架构
From this architecture, we can see that it is actually a relatively similar architecture to other Linux desktop environments
从这份架构可以看到其实他还是一个相对和其他 Linux 桌面环境的架构基本上还是类似的
.It has been more than a year since the release of UKUI3.0
从去年UKUI3.0发布至今已有一年多了
During this year's development time, the UKUI development team has mainly increased the development of the tablet mode
在这一年的开发时间里面UKUI开发团队又主要做了一个平板
.For the tablet mode, we also carried out an exploration and practice of a market project at the same time
针对平板模式我们同时也进行了一个市场倾向项目的一个探索和实践
Here is a brief introduction to everyone
这里给大家简单介绍一下
In order to support the tablet mode
为了支持平板模式
first we will add a better support for the touch functions
首先我们会增加对触摸功能的一个更好的支持
In addition to the common single-finger touch click, long press and swipe
除了常见的一个单指的触摸的点击、长按以及划动之外
It also supports multi-finger and different touch gestures
还支持多指以及不同的触摸的手势
It including from there will be different special effects and functions when sliding into each edge of the screen
包括从屏幕的各个边缘滑入会有不同的一些特效和功能
In addition to enhancing the touch functions
除了对触摸功能增强之外
We also plan to conduct a unified management of all input events in the system
我们还计划对系统所有的一个输入事件进行了统一的管理
.In addition to including keyboard and mouse, touch pad touch and stylus, etc
除了包括键盘鼠标、触摸板触摸以及手写笔等等
it will do a unified management to unify a function of various input methods
会做一个统一的管理来统一各种输入方式的一个功能
Our touch solution started with the Touchegg
我们的触摸方案在开始是使用的 Touchegg 的方案
The Touchegg mainly contains two parts
Touchegg 方案主要是包含两部分
One is an application event filter implemented in X
一个是在 X 中实现了一个应用事件过滤器
and the Touchegg itself
以及 Touchegg 开源方案本身
Toucegg and X share a white list
Touchegg 和 X 共用一个白名单
and then X server will block the touch events of the applications in the white list
然后 X 会对白名单的应用的触摸事件进行拦截
and according to the applications in the white list, Touchegg add touch support for them
再由 Touchegg 对白名单中的应用做触摸支持
The touch event is analyzed and processed by Touchegg
由 Touchegg 对触摸事件进行分析和处理
the corresponding gesture actions are executed
执行对应的手势动作
or the touch event is converted into an X mouse event
或者是将touch的事件转换成 X 鼠标事件
and then sent to the application in the white list
再发给白名单中的应用
Several problems have been found
实践中发现了几个问题
one is that some touch bugs cannot be fixed through Touchegg
一个就是说一些触摸的bug通过 Touchegg 这种方案不能运用
and they need to be modified with X to deal with them, and it is very annoying
需要配合 X 来再进行修改就处理起来很麻烦
Secondly, in addition to X
其次呢就说除了 X
we also ported the X+Touchegg solution to Wayland
我们也是将 X 加 Touchegg 这个方案移植到了 Wayland 上
to supported Wayland
也做了对 Wayland 的支持
but we still need to re-develop some of the displays and these input interfaces required by Touchegg.
但还要再重新开发 Touchegg 需要的一些显示和这些 input 的接口
There are so many problems
就这个问题比较多
In terms of stability and security
还有就是一个稳定性和安全方面
Touchegg has relatively high power requirements
Touchegg  的权限要求比较高
There may be some security risks
可能会存在一些安全的风险
and some shortcomings that limit the stability of Wayland and X
以及限制支持 Wayland、 X  这种方式的稳定性的一些缺陷
So based on this, we finally gave up the Touchegg solution
所以基于此呢我们最后还是放弃了 Touchegg 这个方案
After the implementation of Touchegg, we create a new solution called Touch Manager
在 Touchegg 实现之后呢我们自己又写了一个新的方案叫 Touch Manager
The new solution is mainly divided into two parts
新方案主要是分为两个部分
one is the global touch gesture
一个是全局触摸手势
another is the internal gesture of the application
一个是应用的内部手势
Global touch gestures are mainly implemented by Kwin
全局触摸手势主要由 Kwin 来实现
and then these events are sent to the gesture manager
然后把这些事件发到手势管理器
and the gesture manager will send the gestures to each gesture recognizer
手势管理器会将手势发送给每个手势识别器
Some recognizers merge into a gesture pool
所有的识别器汇成一个手势的竞技场
as long as there is a gesture recognizer whose gesture is satisfied
只要有一个手势识别器他的手势被满足
then the gesture manager can perform the gesture action
那么手势管理器就可以执行该手势动作
and no longer continue to distribute touch events to other gesture recognizers
就不再将触摸事件继续向其他的手势识别器处分发
That is, move other gestures out of this gesture pool
也就是将其他的手势移出这个手势竞技场
In addition, the application of internal gestures is a gesture recognition that is realized through plug-ins
另外一个应用内部手势是通过插件来实现的一个手势识别
Take the Qt application as an example
比如说支持对 Qt 来讲
The gesture recognition plug-in is similar to a QPA plug-in
手势识别插件呢就是类似于一个 QPA 的一个插件
This plug-in will be loaded in all Qt applications
在所有 Qt 的应用里都会加载这个插件
all events sent to the qt application
这样的话就会所有发送给 Qt 应用的事件
will be monitored by this gesture plug-in before being acquired by the internal widget  of the application
都会被应用内部的 Widget 获取前会被这个手势插件来去监听到
This plug-in will analyze and process the behavior of touch events
这个插件就会对触摸事件进行行为的分析和处理
and then under certain circumstances, it can achieve some gesture effects
然后在特定情况下呢就可以实现一些手势的效果
For example, we have implemented an inertial scrolling for all scrollbar
比如我们实现了对所有的一个滚动条实现一个惯性的滚动
The new scheme now has several advantages
新方案现在我觉得有几个优势
one is that the new scheme mainly handles gestures inside Kwin
一个就是新的方案其实它是主要是在 Kwin 内部进行手势的处理
It no longer needs an external exposure interface like Touchegg
不再需要像 Touchegg 一样做一个外挂一样向外暴露接口
which is more secure  and the processing of the window
安全性更高而且对窗口的处理
especially the special effects of the window movement will be very convenient
尤其是对窗口的移动啊特效啊这些会很方便而且扩展也很方便
Then, the gesture registration of the new scheme is also more flexible
然后就是新方案的手势注册也比较灵活
because it adopts the concept of a gesture pool
因为采用了一个手势竞技场的概念
and each gesture corresponds to a separate gesture recognizer
每个手势都对应一个单独的手势识别器
which can be registered, unregistered and other specific gestures at will
可以任意的注册、注销等一些特定的手势
Because the new solution is based on Kwin
新的方案由于是基于 Kwin
it will have a better effect in supporting Wayland
所以在对Wayland的支持中会有更好的一个效果
It can naturally get a higher authority
可以天生拿到一个更高的权限
and it is also more controllable for some conflicts between the edge global time and the window title bar
对于边缘全局的时间和窗口标题栏的一些冲突呢也更加可控
Moreover, the current solution adopts the form of plug-in for Qt and GTK applications
而且就是现在方案对于 Qt 和 GTK 应用是采用了插件的形式
Plug and play as long as some corresponding touch plug-ins are installed
只要安装了一些相对应的触摸插件就可以即插即用
It will keep the original files
而且不会破坏原有的文件
If an application does not want to use the plug-in
如果某个应用程序不想使用插件
then in fact the application only needs to declare an attribute to refuse to use the corresponding plug-in
那么其实应用程序只要本身自己添加一个属性来拒绝使用相对应的插件就可以
At present, we have developed a plug-in for Qt and GTK,
当前我们现在已经针对 Qt 和GTK开发了一个插件
which realizes some gesture animations in part of the program
实现了部分的程序内部的一些手势动效
The Touch Manager program is still in its infancy
Touch Manager 这个方案我们现在还是刚起步中
Mainly by touch
主要是以触摸
Realization of gesture function by touch
以触摸的手势功能实现
There is still a lot of work to be done afterwards
后续还有很多工作要做
For example, an animation effect that is a gesture will be added gradually
比如说一个是手势的一个动画效果会后续逐步添加
Then we also plan to put the touchpad
然后我们也计划会把触摸板
and pressure sensitive pens in the Touch Manager.
以及压感笔全部纳入 Touch Manager 的一个管理
Will all touch some gesture events a from the design implementation and management in terms of
将所有的触摸一些手势事件一个从设计上设计实现和管理上来讲
Support and management can also be unified
也能统一的进行支持和管理
Two basic forms one is the PC mode and one is the tablet mode
两大基本形态一个是 PC 模式一个是平板模式
In the real world
在实际的应用生态中
There are actually more like the tent model,
其实还存在更多的像帐篷模式、
book mode, which will produce different states through different rotation angles and screen positions
书本模式这些通过不同的旋转角度和屏幕的位置会产生不同的一些状态
These are the things that our operating systems need to respond to and work with
这些我们操作系统需要去响应和配合
So we developed a state management component to listen for changes in the underlying hardware state
因此我们就开发了一个状态管理的一个组件来监听底层硬件状态的变化
Such as the state of the gyroscope, laptop plug
比如陀螺仪、笔记本盖子的状态
and filter out the current required state data by calculation
并通过计算过滤出当前所需要的状态数据
Gives us the current state the system should be in
给出我们当前系统应该处于哪个状态
Synchronization provided to the application
同步提供给应用
This solution is actually managed by a session daemon at the beginning
这个方案呢其实最开始我们是用的一个 session daemon 进行管理
The flipping action and some anti-shake handling are done in the session daemon
对翻折动作和一些防抖处理都在 session daemon 里面去做的
But session daemon as a configuration management service should not take on this function
但是 session daemon 作为一个配置管理服务不应该承担这个职能
And this is too coupled to the hardware
而且这个对硬件的耦合性太高
So we later made it a separate service for state management
所以后来我们又把它单独提供一个状态管理的服务
This service mainly provides the following functions
这个服务主要是提供以下的功能
One is to provide a basic interface for switching between PC and tablet mode
一就是提供pc平板模式一个基本的切换的接口
For all system components and applications such as input methods to use
给系统的所有组件及应用比如输入法去使用
Because the input method actually has to provide both PC mode and tablet mode
因为输入法其实也要同时提供pc模式和平板模式
The function interface and response of these two modes of input method are completely different
这两种模式的输入法的功能界面和响应是完全不一样的
So the input method needs to be adjusted in time with the pc mode and tablet mode
所以输入法需要及时的配合pc模式和平板模式进行调整
In addition, this model solution can shield the hardware differences
另外呢这种模式方案可以屏蔽硬件的差异性
Unify different hardware platforms for uniform processing
统一不同的硬件平台进行统一处理
In addition, we also want to unify the state management entrance and exit as well as the state switching logic for unified implementation management
另外呢也是想统一的把状态管理的出入口以及状态的切换逻辑进行统一的实现管理
This development of UKUI's new tablet mode of control in
这种开发UKUI新的平板模式的控制中
We also participated and combined with a real product project to do
我们同时也参与和结合了一个实际的产品项目来去做
This is a Kylin, Intel, Tencent, HP for the education industry
这是一个麒麟、Intel、腾讯、惠普面向教育行业
For k12 users
比如 k12 用户
Launched an exclusive educational learning notebook
推出了一个专属的教育学习的笔记本
This is a four-way cooperation
这边这个是四方合作
Intel is mainly responsible for the hardware driver chip including optimization from performance and power consumption
其中 Intel 主要是负责硬件的驱动芯片包括从性能和功耗上进行优化
Then Tencent mainly provides one of the software implementations for the education industry
然后腾讯主要提供其中的一个教育行业的软件实现
HP provided hardware design of the product including user product research and marketing
惠普的提供者和对产品的硬件设计包括用户的产品调研以及市场推广
Kylin is mainly responsible for the whole system integration
麒麟主要负责整个的系统整合
Absorb and integrate the resources and technologies provided by the other three
吸收整合其他三家提供的资源和技术
Also apply UKUI to the latest technological achievements
同时将 UKUI 应用于最新的技术成果
to the latest products
应用到最新产品中去
This product is actually a multi-modal
这个产品其实是一个多模式的
It supports both PC and tablet modes
它支持 PC 和平板两种模式
这就是对操作系统提出了一个更高的要求
这就是对操作系统提出了一个更高的要求
This is placing a higher demand on the operating system
要求它同时支持pc和平板两种模式
So we'll have UKUI's new tablet mode coming into being
所以我们会有 UKUI 新的平板模式应运而生
In addition to the two main modes of PC and tablet
除了 PC 和平板两大模式之外
In fact, this whole device it's screen support 360 degree rotation
其实这个整个设备中它是屏幕支持 360 度旋转
Then let's say it actually generates more patterns
那就说它实际会产生更多的模式
For example, laptop mode, standing mode, tent mode, book mode and tablet mode
比如说笔记本模式、站立模式、帐篷模式、书本模式还有平板模式
For such a variety of modes, UKUI is also tailored to the actual device and actual needs
针对这么多种模式，UKUI 也是针对实际的设备和实际的需求
A lot of optimization and restructuring of the flat mode and multi-mode switching
对平板模式和多模式切换进行了大量的优化和结构调整
Finally, it provides a good multi-mode and free switching of a functional experience
最后都能提供了一个良好的多模式和自由切换的一个功能体验
This product is mainly for the online education industry
这款产品主要是面向在线的教育行业
The current mass production by HP is already on sale
当前已经是由惠普量产上市销售了
UKUI is equipped with a variety of in-depth optimizations and features
其中搭载了 UKUI 是有各种深度的优化和特性
Some new features will also be synced to Ubuntu Kylin open source OS
一些新的特性也会同步到优麒麟的开源操作系统上去
We will continue to improve it in the future
以后后续也会不断地去给它完善
Supports both PC and tablet modes
同时支持 PC 和平板模式
This notebook is able to support 360 degree rotation
这个笔记本是可以支持360度旋转
When the flip of the 360-degree rotation screen flip will automatically cut back to maintain the flat mode
当翻转的360度旋转屏幕翻转后就会自动切回维持到平板模式
Also supports pressure sensitive pen in addition to touch
同时除了触摸外还支持压感笔
In addition to the two common PC and tablet modes it can also support the tent upside down mode
除了两种常见的pc和平板模式之外它还可以支持帐篷倒立的模式
Even the 90 degree upright book mode
甚至是90度竖立的书本模式
In addition to the validation of a basic function of our UKUI tablet mode in this product project
在这个产品项目中除了我们UKUI平板模式的一个基本功能的验证之外
We have also made some other optimizations including for the input method
我们还做了一些其他的一些优化包括针对输入法的
Because it supports both PC and tablet input
因为同时支持 PC 和平板的输入
Need to do some optimization and some processing and enhancement of the input method framework
需要对输入法框架做一些优化和一些处理和增强
At the same time, the Bluetooth back connection has also done some optimization
同时对蓝牙回连也做了一些优化
The power consumption of the entire UKUI desktop environment has also been optimized through a round of
通过对整个UKUI的桌面环境的一个功耗也做了一轮优化
You can see that this data is in fact much more optimized for our 3.0 release
可以看到这个数据其实针对我们 3.0 的时候性能优化提高了很多
Here are some of the relevant features introduced in the flat mode
下面给大家具体介绍一下在平板模式中引入的一些相关的特性
First PC mode
首先电脑模式
PC mode mainly enhances the interactive experience of touch
电脑模式主要是强化了对触摸的交互体验
That is, some changes to the layout of the pattern, the size and the range of touch to do some optimization
也就是改变了一些图案的布局、大小以及触控的范围做了些优化
Also added sidebar design
同时增加了侧边栏的设计
Because a lot of some messages pop-in, storage and mode of the quick switch all put into the sidebar this quick entrance
因为很多一些消息的弹入、收纳以及模式的快速切换全部放到了侧边栏这个快速入口
The completely new tablet mode has a much simpler UI design
完全新增的平板模式它的 UI 则设计更为简洁
The entire applications icon has been redesigned
整个的应用图标进行了重新的设计
The layout and spacing are all designed and implemented according to the operating experience of the tablet
以及布局间距全部是按照平板的操作体验进行设计和实现的
Also added a widget plugin to an area of the homepage
同时主页也增加了一个小工具插件的一个区域
You can place some common plug-ins
可以放置一些常用的插件
These small plug-ins also support pin
这些小插件同时也支持收纳功能
You can easily and quickly hide these small plugins by swiping
可以通过滑动去方便的快速的去隐藏这些小插件
Both PC mode and tablet mode exist
同时存在 PC 模式和平板模式
Then its mode switching can be switched to the corresponding mode by automatically detecting the form of the hardware
那么它的模式切换可以通过自动侦测硬件的形态来切换到对应的模式
Also users can go through the sidebar and click
同时用户也可以通过侧边栏去点击
to manually switch between tablet mode and PC mode
手动切换平板模式和 PC 模式
At the same time one of the biggest differences of the tablet mode is the display of the application
同时平板模式最大的一个区别就是对应用的展现形式
The display of the flat mode is in the form of a single window with full screen
平板模式的展现形式以单窗口全屏的形式
This allows the application to maximize a tablet state experience
这样使应用可以最大化的得到一个平板状态的一个体验
Meanwhile, the sidebar can be called out by sliding out from the far right side of the screen to the left side
同时侧边栏则是从屏幕的最右侧向左侧滑出即可以呼出
It contains a lot of shortcuts
它包含了很多的快捷键
Easy to switch between networks and modes and to adjust brightness and sound
很方便进行网络和模式的切换以及亮度和声音的调整
The sidebar also includes a message organizer and message alert function
同时侧边栏还包括了消息的收纳和消息的提醒功能
Convenient for users to quickly view system messages and application messages
方便用户快速的查看系统消息和应用消息
It is also possible to jump in time
也可以及时的跳转
Another feature that comes with tablet mode is the new task switching, multitasking view
平板模式带来的另一个特性就是新的任务切换，多任务视图
Due to the nature of tablet mode is the need for a touch-friendly multi-tasking view
由于平板模式的特性就是需要有一个方便触摸使用的一个多任务视图
Easily switch between tasks and close tasks using gestures
可以很方便的使用手势进行任务的切换和任务的关闭
File Manager in tablet mode compared to PC mode
在平板模式下的文件管理器和 PC 模式相比
We didn't make too many interface changes to it
我们并没有对他进行太多的界面上的一个修改
Rather, it is more optimized for his touch operation
而是更多的优化了他的触摸的操作
Added checkboxes and some functions related to the right click with the finger selected
增加了复选框以及手指选中打开右键的相关的一些功能
Making touch easier to use
使触摸更易用
We have also added a global search function
同时我们还新增了一个全局搜索功能
By swiping down with four fingers you can immediately drag out the global search
通过四指向下滑动就可以立即拖出全局搜索
Accurate matching of English and Chinese and easy search of local and web resources
可以精准的匹配中英文以及方便本地和网络资源的搜索
As you can see the tablet mode is actually a big job is to add a new way of interaction
大家可以看到平板模式其实很大的一个工作就是新增一种新的交互方式
On the basis of the traditional mouse keyboard and touchpad
在传统的鼠标键盘以及触控板的基础上
Need to add touch gesture power and pressure sensitive pen support for OS usage
需要增加触摸手势力以及压感笔对操作系统的使用的支持
What we currently do is
我们当前做到的是
The user can alternately use the mouse, gesture, touchpad, and pressure-sensitive pen in any PC mode and tablet mode to operate the device
在用户在任意的 PC 模式和平板模式下都可以交替的使用鼠标、手势、触摸板、压感笔等设备进行操作
While operating with hand gestures or pressure sensitive pen
在用手势或压感笔操作的同时
The mouse pointer will be automatically hidden
鼠标指针就会自动隐藏
And for the touchpad and we use the touch finger to operate basically the same functional behavior
而且针对触摸板和我们用触摸手指去进行的操作基本上功能行为是一致的
and some of the above mentioned touch interaction on a tablet mode support
和上面讲到的一些触摸交互上的一个平板模式支持
Here is also a brief introduction to two interesting little features
这里还简单介绍两个有趣的小功能
One is the eye protection mode, while we will automatically
一个是护眼模式，同时我们会自动
UKUI will automatically switch between dark and light themes according to the current one time
UKUI会根据当前的一个时间自动切换深色和浅色主题
Also supports user-defined screen brightness and theme color shades
同时还支持用户自定义屏幕亮度以及主题色彩深浅
In addition, we can identify whether the user is currently staring at the screen through AI recognition technology
另外我们通过AI识别技术，可以识别用户当前是否在盯着屏幕
When the user continuously looks at the screen for a certain time or the user's eyes are too close to the screen
当用户连续注视屏幕一定时间或者用户的眼睛距离屏幕太近
We will also pop up a reminder when the sitting position is not correct
就坐姿不正确的时候我们也会弹出提醒
Remind users to use it for too long
提醒用户使用时间过久
Or sitting in the wrong position
或者是坐姿不对
Too close to the screen will harm the eyesight of such reminders
太靠近屏幕会伤害视力这种提醒
At the same time, we also support the intelligent use of scenes according to the user to adjust the color temperature to reduce a stimulation of the eyes
同时我们还支持智能的根据用户使用的场景来调整色温减少对眼睛的一个刺激
At the same time, we have a light sensor and a color sensor in conjunction with
同时我们在光线传感器和色彩传感器的一个配合下
We can automatically adjust the color temperature of the screen according to a scene the user is in
我们可以做到自动根据用户所在的一个场景来自适应调节屏幕的色温
to reduce an irritation to the eyes
来减少对眼睛的一个刺激
Another interesting feature point is the unified identity
另一个有趣的功能点就是统一的身份认证
Turning a traditional local account into a cloud-based WeChat account
将原来传统的一个本地账号变成了一个云端微信账号
Users can directly take out their cell phones and scan the code to log into the operating system
用户可以直接拿出手机扫码登录操作系统
OK, the above briefly introduces a current status of our UKUI
ok，以上简单介绍了一下我们 UKUI 当前的一个现状
The following briefly discusses one of our future plans for the near future
下面简单谈一下我们未来近期的一个规划
First of all, for the tablet mode, in fact, the big difference with the PC mode is that he needs a very powerful notification system
首先针对平板模式，其实和pc模式差异较大的就是他需要一个很强大的通知系统
We will continue to improve the entire notification system.
后续我们会继续的完善整个的通知的体系
Also the operation of a tablet will be further enhanced
同时对一个平板的操作还会再增强
For example, a drag and drop of desktop icons, group management including the display of some applications
比如说对桌面图标的一个拖拽、分组管理包括一些应用的展现
One of the great features of the tablet mode is that it only shows one application in the foreground at the same time
平板模式有一个很大的特色就是它同时只会展现一个前台的应用程序
The rest of the program is in the background
其余程序都在后台
Then its application lifecycle management is completely different from the PC model
那么它的应用的一个生命周期的管理是和 PC 模式完全不一样的
Subsequently we need to target it
后续我们需要针对性的对它进行处理
At the same time, UKUI3.1 is still lacking in some animation effects in tablet mode
同时现在我们 UKUI3.1 在平板模式上面一些动画效果还比较欠缺
We will also continue to improve afterwards
之后我们也会继续完善
Tablet mode can be more demanding on power management than PC mode
平板模式对电源管理要求会比 PC 模式更为苛刻
Because its scenario requires
因为它的使用场景
low power consumption
一定是需要低功耗
Such a state of power saving mode
省电模式这样一个状态
This is also where we need to focus on optimizing it later
这也是我们后续需要重点对它优化的地方
If you input at the same time, one is pressure-sensitive pen and touch input method
同时输入的话，一个是压感笔以及触摸的输入法
The whole input experience is also the direction we need to further optimize
整个的输入体验也是我们需要进一步优化的方向
Also a support for AI including the entire desktop environment for voice and motion interaction
同时对AI的一个支持包括整个桌面环境对语音和动作的交互
There is also an AI-based data search
还有一个是基于 AI 的数据搜索
These are one of the directions we need to explore subsequently
这些都是后续我们需要探索的一个方向
ok thank you all very much
ok，非常感谢大家
The above is a technical share of mine today welcome to follow Ubuntu Kylin
以上就是我今天的一个技术分享欢迎大家来关注优麒麟
Follow UKUI to get involved in the development of UKUI and Ubuntu Kylin
关注 UKUI 来参与到 UKUI 和优麒麟的开发中
Okay, thank you all
好，谢谢大家